#### Contact

courtney.edwards@phhs.org

www.linkedin.com/in/courtney-edwards-2885a960 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Public Health

Healthcare Information Technology Critical Care

### Certifications

Critical Care Registered Nurse (Adult) (CCRN-A)

Trauma Certified Registered Nurse (TCRN)

**NEA-BC** 

Certified Emergency Nurse (CEN)

# Courtney Edwards

Trauma Outreach Education, Injury Prevention, & Research Manager at Parkland Health & Hospital System Wylie, Texas

## Summary

Innovative leader with experience in working among people, building collaboration, and improving programs and processes in a leading academic teaching organization. Adapt in driving performance improvement initiatives, better patient and work staff outcomes to strengthening the healthcare system.

- Infrastructure to drive programming
- Facilitate positive social change
- Regulatory compliance & quality
- Oversight and operational development
- Facility transition & planning

## Experience

Parkland Hospital

14 years 3 months

Trauma Outreach Education, Injury Prevention, & Clinical Research Manager

June 2007 - Present (13 years)

Manages the Outreatch Education and Injury Prevention programs to ensure Trauma Center verification and designation as a Level 1 Trauma Center with the American College of Surgeons and the Texas Department of State Health Services

Trauma Nurse Clinician

March 2006 - June 2007 (1 year 4 months)

Clinical team member providing for the intial stabilization of a trauma patient and throughout the continuum of care encompassing clinical expertise, psychosocial crisis intervention, family interaction and system performance to improve and expedite the hospital stay of the injuried patient

Parkland Hospital

RN II Staff Nurse Emergency Services

February 2004 - March 2005 (1 year 2 months)

Provided direct patient care in an urban Level 1 Emergency Department with over 143,000 visits in 2005

## Education

Texas Christian University

Doctor of Nursing Practice, Nursing · (2016 - 2018)

The University of Texas at Arlington

Master of Science Nursing (MSN) · (2008 - 2012)

University of North Texas Health Science Center at Fort Worth Master of Public Health (MPH) · (2008 - 2012)

Baylor University
Bachelor of Science in Nursing